# **CLYDE A. MCNEIL II**

# TS/SCI Active Clearance | Web Developer | UX/UI | Graphic & Visual Design

☑ CLYDE.MCNEIL.25@GMAIL.COM in LinkedIn ▶ Portfolio ♠ GitHub Bē Behance \*\*\* Fiverr

# **OBJECTIVE**

Proud soon to be Veteran, served 21 years in the United States Air Force transitioning from boots to tech. Computer Science graduate that is highly motivated and a versatile designer/developer with mobile-first responsive development in mind. Willing to learn more and hone newly acquired skillsets. Experienced in collaborating in teams under stressful environments and ready to contribute to my future employer's vision.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor in Science/Computer Science, Southwestern College

Nov 2021

Associate in Applied Science/Mechanical and Electrical Technology,

Mar 2018

Community College of the Air Force

# **CERTIFICATES**

Google UX Design Certificate ☑

Meta Social Media Marketing ☑

CalArts Fundamentals of Graphic Design ☑

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## Student, Deep Dive Bootcamp Full Stack Web Developer,

Jul 2022 – present

Devoted 10 Weeks/400 hrs to intense coding program, certified in software architecture principles.

Virtual

# Squad Finder App, Github Link 2 8 Weeks

- Collaboratively worked and designed in 4 member development team building frontend/backend in delivering social media app for gamers under the Agile methodology.
- Programmed entity relationship diagram (ERD), synced Twitch API database, PostgreSQL data management.

## CMc25 Personal Website Portfolio, Github Link 2 7 Weeks

- Self-branding in the design and development of website features showcasing graphic design, UX/UI design, web developer, video production, and audio production skillsets.
- Implemented wireframing, typography, color theory, and Gerstalt design principles for layout of portfolio site.
- Utilized newly acquired/wrote structured, tested, readable code in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, JQuery, and Bootstrap.
- Delivered in 7 weeks, features Mailgun email functionality, reCAPTCHA secured, deployed site with Digital Ocean.

**Student, Google UX Design,** Acquired user experience design/research principals, mockups, prototypes, wireframes, storyboards, & usability tests.

Mar 2022 – May 2022 Virtual

# Custom Tees, Case Study ☑, Prototype Link ☑, 2 Weeks

• Mobile/Website for users to design and order their custom designed t-shirt.

## **Restaurant Finder, Case Study** ☑, *Prototype Link* ☑, 3 Weeks

• Mobile/Website for finding a restaurant near you.

# Nutri-Kids, Case Study ☑, Prototype Link ☑, 2 Weeks

• Mobile/Website to teach children about nutrition through mini games.

# **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

## **Soft Skills**

Problem Solver, Logical Thinker, Attention to Detail, Resourceful, Adaptable, Leadership, Integrity, Collaborator, Team Player, Empathy, Social Skills, Imaginative, Reliable, Self-Motivating, Resilient

# **UX** Design

Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch

#### 3D Artist

ZBrush, Blender, Unreal Engine 5, Character Creator 4, iClone 8, Daz3D

# **Audio Production**

Pro Tools, Cubase, Studio One, FL Studio, Reason, Maschine, Native Instruments, Mixing, Mastering

#### Web Developer

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, Git, Github, MySQL, DevOps, Docker, Bootstrap

# **Graphic Design**

Photoshop, Illustrator, Clip Studio, Affinity Suite, Canva, Envato

# Motion/Video Production

Davinci Resolve, Adobe After Effects, Wondershare Filmora Pro

## **Productivity**

Microsoft Office Suite

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Founder | Principle | Freelance | Graphic & Visual Designer, Krucial Studios LLC

Entrepreneurial spirit led to the formation of Krucial Studios, provided graphic designs, logos, motion graphics, and animation services to over 50 clients.

May 2019 – present San Antonio, USA

# Hall Insurance Commercial , Video Editor | Motion Graphics

- Led 2-man team in providing motion graphics and video editing services for Hall Insurance in 2
  weeks.
- Informed the Raleigh/Durham/Chapel Hill, NC region on insurance benefits, estimated at 100K populous.

# Master Sergeant, USAF

 Served faithfully and honorably for 21 years with distinction, including 11 overseas tours of duty (Japan, Iraq, Qatar, Afghanistan, Korea, United Kingdom, Germany, Denmark, India, Congo, and Malta) and four combat tours. Jan 2001 – present San Antonio, USA

# Emergency Manager, USAF

- Rewrote Emergency Action Plan; hardened evacuation and active shooter event plans and armed 3,000 personnel with a more effective crisis response.
- Directed major renovations and repairs to structural, electrical, plumbing and HVAC systems at 85 worldwide locations.
- Identified and developed projects and resolved critical infrastructure deficiencies at 165 global Intelligence, Surveillance and Reconnaissance (ISR) facilities valued at \$1B+.

Oct 2019 – Nov 2022 San Antonio, USA

# **HVAC Operations Manager,** USAF

- Oversaw Heating, Ventilation and Air Conditioning (HVAC) planning, installation, maintenance, repair, and labor requirements for national level operations.
- Rewrote Air Force mechanical systems standards; eliminated failure nodes and increased system reliability by 50%.
- Co-authored Mission Critical Facilities Engineering Standard document; analyzed and applied technical expertise that standardized 200 worldwide facilities and ensured command, control, communications, computers, intelligence, surveillance and reconnaissance (C4ISR) operations.

Oct 2019 – Nov 2022 San Antonio, USA

#### MEAR Project Team Chief, USAF

- Mobile Engineering Alteration and Repair (MEAR) teams provide civil-engineering (CE) technicians cleared for sensitive compartmented information (SCI) to work in secure areas of governmental facilities.
- Managed 12-member team in support of NSA, Department of State, USAF, and other national agencies' global infrastructure.
- Directed major renovations and repairs on all associated HVAC/R and air distribution systems at 85 locations worldwide.

Feb 2016 – Oct 2019 San Antonio, USA

#### HVAC Craftsman, USAF

- Led 44 Japanese national craftsmen on daily heat operations supporting 2,200 facilities valued at \$7.8B.
- Provided 24-hour emergency HVAC/R response and repairs for 12,000 base buildings and 2,100 military family housing units valued at \$7.1B.
- Implemented a 102-mile steam distribution system and annual corrosion control program for 40 industrial steam boilers.

Dec 2010 – Nov 2014 Misawa, Japan